# Deanne Smeaton

LinkedIn Profile

Experienced Software Developer with nearly a decade of experience developing full-stack, client-side and server-side solutions that strive to be the best fit for customers, are secure and perform well. I am self-motivated with excellent communication and organisational skills. I work well under pressure, pay high attention to detail, and am highly collaborative. Alongside personal growth, I find deep satisfaction in guiding fellow team members and supporting their journey towards excellence. I look forward to the prospect of contributing my expertise to a new endeavour, all the while remaining open to learning and growth.

# **Experience**

JANUARY 2022 – PRESENT Developers Institute

# Senior Full Stack and Tech Lead

Mentoring and training the next generation of software developers. Training the PERN and MERN stack and Application Security. The role includes course content creation, workshops, 1:1 mentoring, and providing feedback through code-reviews. Also, part of a team that continually improves the learner experience.

## **KEY AREAS**

## **CLIENT-SIDE COURSE**

Training learners on how to create and design websites starting with HTML, CSS Grid, CSS Flexbox and JavaScript. To how to create react components. I was also part of accessing learners and providing code reviews.

#### **SERVER-SIDE COURSE**

Training learners on how to create server-side solutions in Express by creating REST API, using MongoDB in docker and connecting to the API in React to show the data and post data to save in MongoDB. Taught TDD, using Jest and SuperTest. Also covered how to implement authentication in AuthO and deploy to the cloud using Render. I was also part of accessing learners and providing code reviews.

## **FULL STACK COURSE**

Training learners on how to create a full-stack web solution using PostgreSQL, Express and React. Training on how to dockerise their solutions, creating Open API, testing in react-scripts, Jest, SuperTest, including how to mock, cover authorisation in AuthO and deploy the solution into Render. I was also part of accessing learners and providing code reviews.

# **APPLICATION SECURITY COURSE**

Training learners on how to secure and find security bugs in web applications they create using OWASP top 10. Training them on the importance of security, and how to implement security throughout the software development lifecycle, performing threat assessments, creating security requirements, using tools to scan their code and website. I was also part of accessing learners and providing code-reviews.

FEBRUARY 2016 - JANUARY 2022

**Auckland Council** 

Senior Software Developer (Dec 2017 – Jan 2022)

Web and Mobile Developer (Sep 2016 – Dec 2017)

Associate Web and Mobile Developer (Feb 2016 – Sep 2016)

My role was to support and develop multiple websites and solutions that meet business needs, with data privacy, performance, and security in mind. Maintaining and adding features to both the external websites and internal intranets. I was promoted within two years to a senior for showing my ability to lead and deliver project work with high customer satisfaction.

## **KEY PROJECTS**

## **AUCKLAND LIBRARIES WEBSITE UPGRADE**

# https://www.aucklandlibraries.govt.nz/

Project upgrading the Auckland Libraries website from SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2013 with their new redesign. I worked as part of a team, with my main task to implement the forms which users interact with. This included SharePoint Web Control and implementing services using the Repository Design Pattern in ASP.NET, Bootstrap, JavaScript/jQuery, Azure DevOps.

#### **DARE TO EXPLORE**

Lead Developer creating a SharePoint 2013 website for summer programme 2013 summer programme. This allowed children to complete challenges and write book reviews. This included creating SharePoint Web Controls, implementing services using the Repository Design Pattern in ASP.NET, SharePoint Master page, connecting with external APIs, Bootstrap, JavaScript/jQuery, creating deployment scripts in PowerShell, and Azure DevOps.

#### **RATES GUIDE**

Lead Developer in creating a way for ratepayers to find information on the potential impact on their rates on proposed changes. My role was not only the developer but also the solution designer to create a reusable solution, as this is a yearly event which previously meant creating new solutions each year. I designed the database tables created in Microsoft SQL Server, the ASP.NET Web API and the front-end SharePoint Web Control, which had dynamic properties for content creators to update.

# **PROGRESS AUCKLAND**

# https://progressakl.co.nz/

Part of the development team to create a website that allowed Aucklanders to see construction projects that are planned or currently happening. I worked closely with the GIS team to create a cohesive solution. The website was created in Umbraco, using ASP.NET MVC, Angular, JavaScript/jQuery, Google Maps Service and ArcGIS API. Azure DevOps CI/CD, Azure web app.

# **CITY CENTRE MASTER PLAN**

# https://www.aucklandccmp.co.nz/

Helped finish this project when it was near the end. I was involved in making interactive SVGs. The website was created in Umbraco, using ASP.NET MVC, Angular, JavaScript/jQuery, Azure DevOps CI/CD, Azure web app.

# **CUSTOMER SERVICE KIOSK APPLICATION**

Lead developer tasked to create a solution for Customer Service Centres Kiosk to limit what websites could be viewed and help customers find information on any Council Website. This was two-part solution. I created an admin portal using Umbraco, which allowed the Customer Service team to add, update and delete links for the

kiosks and I developed a Universal Windows Platform (UWP) application using MVVM, which got what websites to show using an ASP.NET Web API. The Umbraco website was hosted on Azure Web App deployed via Azure DevOps CI/CD and the application also connected to Azure Tables.

## **PEST SEARCH**

https://www.tiakitamakimakaurau.nz/protect-and-restore-our-environment/pests-in-auckland/pest-search/

Lead developer migrating old pest search website to the Tiaki Tāmaki Makaurau website. The website was created in Umbraco, using ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, Angular, JavaScript/jQuery, Azure DevOps CI/CD, Azure web app.

## **ENGAGEMENT CALENDAR**

Lead developer for creating a SPFX webpart for our internal SharePoint Online Intranet using React and Typescript. This Calendar showed internal and external events coming up for the Auckland Council Engagement team, allowing them to filter based on event types or location. Connected to a SharePoint List.

## **DEVSEC INITIATIVE**

Lead a focus group to shift security left into our development space. This included creating plans on how to get our website security up to date, creating checklists for any new websites created from learnings from previous security scans, and meeting regularly.

FEBRUARY 2014 - FEBRUARY 2016

Auckland Council

## IS Graduate

A two-year graduate programme where I was given the opportunity to rotate around five different areas of the Information Services department, including Web & Mobile, Database Administration, Service Desk, Project Management and Solution Architecture. Tasked with a mixture of support and project delivery work.

# Other experience

2021

Contract: API Email Service

# **Wove Designs**

Created an API Email Service that connected at checkout to give the front-end developer a better solution when connecting to SendGrid, created the solution using an AWS lambda function in .NET Core.

2022

Prayer App

## **Church Unlimited**

Volunteered my time to work with the front-end developers from Wove Design to create a function for Google Firebase in Node.js, which sends a reminder email for when the users booking is coming up.

# **Skills**

# Non-Technical Skills

- Focused, self-motivated with great time management skills
- Mentoring and providing guidance
- Understanding of OWASP Top 10
- Great understanding SDLC lifecycle
- Agile management practices
- Great knowledge in DevOps and DevSec principles
- Great written and verbal communication skills
- A team player Reliable, committed, and flexible
- ITIL management practices

# **Technical Skills**

- ASP.NET, MVC and .NET Core development in C#
- Creating scalable solutions in Azure
- Developing and architecting web services and APIs
- JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Angular
- Node.js Express
- Experience in multiple CSS frameworks
- Working with SQL and database management
- Using Azure DevOps and GitHub for source repository and CI/CD pipelines
- UWP development

# **Education**

2013

Bachelor of Information and Computer Science | Software Developer Major/AUT

2009-2010

**Bachelor of Computer Systems/EIT** 

Cross credited to AUT

# **Certificates**

2023

Digital and Collaborative Teaching and Learning Micro-credential

2019

**Umbraco Fundamentals** 

2014

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management v3 2020

**Azure Fundamentals** 

2019

**DevOps Foundation** 

2019

**ICAgile Certified Professionals**